<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://techtelegrams.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://techtelegrams.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-25T13:15:58+05:30</updated><id>https://techtelegrams.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Telegrams</title><subtitle>Latest Technology News about Gadgets, Internet and Cloud. #logo : &quot;/assets/images/techtelegrams_logo.png&quot;</subtitle><author><name>Tech Telegrams</name></author><entry><title type="html">Does 4K TV really need to be Smart</title><link href="https://techtelegrams.com/television/Does-4K-TV-really-need-to-be-Smart/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does 4K TV really need to be Smart" /><published>2020-06-24T10:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-24T10:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://techtelegrams.com/television/Does-4K-TV-really-need-to-be-Smart</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://techtelegrams.com/television/Does-4K-TV-really-need-to-be-Smart/">&lt;p&gt;Television is a major entertainment in Household for more than half century
years. Even now it is one of most utilized thing for entertainment in every
households in this
planet. Now 4K LED TV with larger screen sizes are becoming more affordable.
At this time of writing lot of affordable 4K LED TV with 65 inch screen size
are available in the price range of 50,000 to 65,000 INR, which is half the
price of what was the selling price in couple of years ago. That too with
Smart features using Android TV OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-4k-tv-better-than-fhd-tv&quot;&gt;Does 4K TV better than FHD TV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now there are very less 4K content available on the VoD services. By
considering this buyer might prefer to buy FHD TV rather than 4K TV. But that
is not correct because&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4K TVs are also affordable with price slightly higher than FHD.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buying 4K TV will be future proof, as in future lot more 4K content will
be available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly FHD TV panels are not widely manufactured, so FHD TV
available in market are old technology products or even manufactured few years
back. So choosing 4K TV is the better option over FHD right now&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;led-vs-qled-vs-oled-options-in-4k-tv&quot;&gt;LED vs QLED vs OLED options in 4K TV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4K LED TV panels are coming with 3 variants normal backlit LED, QLED and OLED.
The difference between these 3 variants are quite discussed in multiple online
forums. This post does not cover that, instead it helps to choose the right one.
In terms of picture quality OLED is better than QLED and QLED is better than
LED. Prices of these 3 variants are also categorized based on this picture
quality. If the budget is limited, then even choosing LED 4K TV with HDR10 will
give better picture quality. Mainly for those who upgrade their old HD or FHD
LED TVs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-4k-tv-really-need-to-be-smart&quot;&gt;Does 4K TV really need to be Smart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now all 4K TVs are coming with Smart Features with Android OS. But at this time
this is not even needed, because there are lot of Android 4K TV Boxes (for 
example Mi Box) available in this market. And also now a days DTH providers in
India (Airtel, Tata Sky) have launched Android TV Set Top Box which delivers
both online content (with Android TV OS) and cable TV content from Dish. So
now a days TV manufactured should not focus more on adding Android TV OS or
chipset (Processor, Memory and Storage) to run Android TV OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel &lt;strong&gt;keeping Android TV OS build into 4K TV is unnecessary&lt;/strong&gt;. Because
keeping Android TV OS out of TV will benifit in lot of ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prices of TV will come down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power consumption of TV will reduce.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TV will become more thinner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat dissipation from TV will be lesser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly hardware (Processor, Memory) to run Android TV needs
periodic update to run latest OS and Apps for every 2 years (like Mobile
Phone). If Smart TV feature (Android TV OS) is in the form of external box,
then it will be
economical for user to upgrade the hardware every 1 or 2 year. But upgrading
TV every 1 or 2 year is not economical. Because TV buyers in India tend to use
a TV for minimum 5 to 10 years. Some try to use more than 10 years. &lt;strong&gt;So 4K TV
should be manufactured without any Smart Features (Android TV OS or any other
OS)&lt;/strong&gt;, that will benefit the buyer in lot of aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does any 4K TV available in market without Smart Feature ? The answer is No.
I feel TV OEM manufactures are not looking in this point of view. In today’s
market if anyone manufactures 4K TV without Smart OS then he will be the
winner in this market.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok Karmegam</name></author><category term="Television" /><category term="SmartTV" /><category term="Android" /><category term="Apple" /><summary type="html">Television is a major entertainment in Household for more than half century years. Even now it is one of most utilized thing for entertainment in every households in this planet. Now 4K LED TV with larger screen sizes are becoming more affordable. At this time of writing lot of affordable 4K LED TV with 65 inch screen size are available in the price range of 50,000 to 65,000 INR, which is half the price of what was the selling price in couple of years ago. That too with Smart features using Android TV OS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple jumps from Intel to ARM: One App to run on iPhone, iPad and Mac</title><link href="https://techtelegrams.com/apple/Apple-Jumps-from-Intel-to-ARM-One-App-to-run-on-iPhone-iPad-and-Mac/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple jumps from Intel to ARM: One App to run on iPhone, iPad and Mac" /><published>2020-06-23T17:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-23T17:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://techtelegrams.com/apple/Apple-Jumps-from-Intel-to-ARM-One-App-to-run-on-iPhone-iPad-and-Mac</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://techtelegrams.com/apple/Apple-Jumps-from-Intel-to-ARM-One-App-to-run-on-iPhone-iPad-and-Mac/">&lt;p&gt;Apple’s Mac Computers (MacBook, iMac and Mac Pro) are currently running on
Intel Processors which is going to be changed to run on in-house ARM processors.
By this change Apple can deliver higher security, stability, performance and
lesser power consumption with in-house ARM processors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;history-of-mac-computers&quot;&gt;History of Mac Computers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mac Computer was first launched in 1990 and it served three decades to the
human mankind for personal computing needs, and it evolved to various kind of
Mac Computers like Mac Pro, iMac and Macbook to suit the human needs. Initially
in 1990 Mac started its journey with Motorola Processors, later in 1995 it
jumps to IBM’s PowerPC and after a decade (in 2005) it jumps to intel x86.
Today in 2020 after 3 decades it jumps to ARM processors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;one-app-to-run-on-iphone-ipad-and-mac&quot;&gt;One App to run on iPhone, iPad and Mac&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this move, Apple claims that most of the iPhone and iPad App will run
smoothly on Mac with ARM chips. And Apple user no need to purchase two
flavours of a same app for iPhone/iPad and Mac. This reduces burden on app
developers as well who develop apps on all the 3 types of Apple products
(iPhone, iPad and Mac).
And also apps which are currently exist only on iPhone/iPad and does not exist
on Mac platform will also be used on Mac devices in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rosetta-2&quot;&gt;Rosetta 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existing x86 based Mac Apps can be &lt;strong&gt;installed on ARM based Mac with the help of
Rosetta 2&lt;/strong&gt;. This gives breathing time for app developers to migrate from x86
to ARM based environment by retaining users. First version of Rosetta was used
by Apple in 2005 when it migrates its Mac product lines from PPC to Intel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mac-app-store&quot;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this move, Apple will achive all Mac Apps distribute under &lt;strong&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/strong&gt;.
Currently that is not the case for Mac device Apps. That means currently
App developers can distribute the Apps by themself to Mac products. But
in future it will not be the case. &lt;strong&gt;All Mac App developers should distribute
the apps via Apple’s Mac App Store&lt;/strong&gt;. Similar to iPhone and iPad App Stores.
And this will allows apple to get
a slice of revenue from Commercial Mac Apps and also it will be able to
control the boundaries of App. Some of the App developers will hesitate to
accept this. But no way other than accepting it if they want to support
Apps on future Mac products.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok Karmegam</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="Arm" /><category term="Intel" /><category term="Laptop" /><category term="Desktop" /><summary type="html">Apple’s Mac Computers (MacBook, iMac and Mac Pro) are currently running on Intel Processors which is going to be changed to run on in-house ARM processors. By this change Apple can deliver higher security, stability, performance and lesser power consumption with in-house ARM processors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazfit Stratos 3 SmartWatch from Huami launched in India</title><link href="https://techtelegrams.com/wearable/Amazfit-Stratos-3-SmartWatch-from-Huami-launched-in-India/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazfit Stratos 3 SmartWatch from Huami launched in India" /><published>2020-06-22T18:20:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-22T18:20:00+05:30</updated><id>https://techtelegrams.com/wearable/Amazfit-Stratos-3-SmartWatch-from-Huami-launched-in-India</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://techtelegrams.com/wearable/Amazfit-Stratos-3-SmartWatch-from-Huami-launched-in-India/">&lt;p&gt;Huami’s Amazfit &lt;a href=&quot;https://in.amazfit.com/pages/amazfit-stratos-3&quot;&gt;Stratos 3&lt;/a&gt;
launched in India today with 80 different sport tracking and with 14 days
battery backup at the price of 13,999 INR. It will be available for purchase
in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flipkart.com/huami-amazfit-stratos-3-smartwatch/p/itm04ac5e6ae66d6?pid=SMWFMQFKRQCHMAC6&amp;amp;lid=LSTSMWFMQFKRQCHMAC6AQXGPO&amp;amp;marketplace=FLIPKART&amp;amp;srno=s_1_2&amp;amp;otracker=search&amp;amp;otracker1=search&amp;amp;fm=SEARCH&amp;amp;iid=01c04efa-7658-4a81-b258-8b441af4c505.SMWFMQFKRQCHMAC6.SEARCH&amp;amp;ppt=sp&amp;amp;ppn=sp&amp;amp;ssid=hc9r50x7ts0000001592831732598&amp;amp;qH=635d4a33e484a304&quot;&gt;Flipkart&lt;/a&gt;
from today 8PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;external-specification&quot;&gt;External Specification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Display: 1.34” Round Transflective Display with 320x320 pixel.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transflective_liquid-crystal_display&quot;&gt;Transflective display&lt;/a&gt;
  is an LCD which reflects and transmits light. Under daylight the display
  acts as reflective display and under dark ambient backlight transmits
  light to the display. This &lt;strong&gt;delivers crystal clear display even under
  daylight condition&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glass: Corning Gorilla Glass 3 with anti fingerprint coating.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strap: Only black sporty strap option available which is silicon strap.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strap Length: 120 mm (long), 75 mm (short)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strap Width: 22 mm&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water Resistance: 5ATM which can survive upto 50 meters depth in water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;External Buttons: Four buttons which can be utilized for complete navigation.
In shivery conditions (after heavy workout or snowy climate) touch screen
navigation can be completely avoided with these 4 buttons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Body: 316L Stainless Steel body with plastic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Case: Diameter 48.6 mm and Thickness 13.44 mm.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weight: 40.0 gram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;internal-specification&quot;&gt;Internal Specification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Processor: 1.2GHz dual-core processor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Memory: 512 MB&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Storage: 2 GB internal storage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Battery (300mAh) life:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Upto 14 days under Ultra Endurance Mode&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Upto 7 days under Smart mode&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When using GPS continuously (mainly to record jogging or cycling distance)
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Upto 35 hours in accurate mode&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Upto 45 hours in balanced mode&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Upto 70 hours in power saving mode&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charging Time: 2.5 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sensors:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;BioTracker™ PPG Bio-Tracking optical senso&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6-axis acceleration sensor&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3-axis geomagnetic sensor&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Air pressure sensor&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connectivity: NFC, GPS/ Glonass, Bluetooth v5.0, and Wi-Fi 802.11 b/g/n
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sony GNSS chips support four different global positioning systems (GPS,
  GLONASS, BEIDOU and GALILEO)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OS: Amazfit OS (An Android based OS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sports: Supports 80 different sport modes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heart rate Monitor: Huami Technology’s proprietary &lt;strong&gt;BioTrackerTM PPG
bio-tracking optical sensor&lt;/strong&gt; delivers accurate heart rate monitor.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Provides warning on higher heart-rate and heart-rate interval.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amazfit-stratos-3-review&quot;&gt;Amazfit Stratos 3 Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 13999 INR Amazfit Stratos 3 is packed with good specs (Accurate Heart rate
sensor, Faster positioning and accurate GPS, monitors 80 different Sports,
Transflective display, Dedicated 4 buttons, 5ATM Water resistance) and good
build quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wearable-device-market-in-india&quot;&gt;Wearable Device Market in India&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far the 95% of Smart Phone users are staying away from Smart Wearable, mainly
because the value user gets out of it is not commendable for the price. Because
most of the Smart Phone users are using mid range Smart phones (10000 to 20000
INR). And spending almost same amount as Smart Phone on Smart Wearable needs
a noticable value other than Step Counts. Because even Smart Phone App can
count the steps which user makes. Indian Smart Phone users are reluctant to put
same amount (10000 to 20000 INR) on wearables for monitoring sleep, heart rate
and physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Indian competitive market
to reach more customer, a Wearable OEM should come with the price tag half of
the mid range Smart Phone price (roughly 5000 to 10000 INR) with good set
of physical activity monitoring. And also other than physical activity tracking
app, much more apps support should come to Wearable OS. For example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A news app which pops and displays news based on user subscribed categories.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cab booking app integration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online Wallets QR code for receiving money. So that user can show his Wallet
QR code to sender without taking out his phone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even QR code scanning with a camera on Wearable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ongoing COVID-19 pandemic gives a warning statement that fitness is the key
to survival against such virus attack against human mankind. So to keep fit 
more and more people will start practicing physical activity on regular
basis that also will boost Wearable device sales in India in upcoming years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok Karmegam</name></author><category term="Wearable" /><category term="Huami" /><category term="Android" /><summary type="html">Huami’s Amazfit Stratos 3 launched in India today with 80 different sport tracking and with 14 days battery backup at the price of 13,999 INR. It will be available for purchase in Flipkart from today 8PM.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No order from Indian Government to ban Chinese App</title><link href="https://techtelegrams.com/internet/No-Order-From-Indian-Goverment-to-ban-Chinese-App/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No order from Indian Government to ban Chinese App" /><published>2020-06-22T00:20:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-22T00:20:00+05:30</updated><id>https://techtelegrams.com/internet/No-Order-From-Indian-Goverment-to-ban-Chinese-App</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://techtelegrams.com/internet/No-Order-From-Indian-Goverment-to-ban-Chinese-App/">&lt;p&gt;A viral memo from NIC (National Informatics Centre) circulating on Indian
social media which states that Government placed an order to ban Chinese
Apps on Google play store and Apple App Store. &lt;strong&gt;This is fake news&lt;/strong&gt;. PIB
(Press Information Bureau) an Indian government agency announced this
as fake memo. This has been anounced by PIB on its official twitter handle
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PIBFactCheck/status/1273923942349041664&quot;&gt;PIBFactCheck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;people-should-avoid-forwarding-unauthentic-message&quot;&gt;People should avoid forwarding unauthentic message&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently these kind of fake news spreading with digital letter format of
Indian Government and also with Government authority signature is quite
common in India. On social media if anyone receives it, immediately it gets
forwarded without verifying the authenticity of the news. It is unethical
behaviour of an Indian Citizen. Receiving legitimate news from authentic News
agency should be trusted and forwarded on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-trust-without-verifying&quot;&gt;Don’t Trust without verifying&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this digital world lot of rumours can be spread by timepassers in social
media (like Whatsapp, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, etc.) to get more likes
and follows. As an India Citizen any such message
received on social media should not be trusted until unless it is
cross verified with authentic News forums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beware of such fake news.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok Karmegam</name></author><category term="Internet" /><category term="Android" /><category term="Apple" /><summary type="html">A viral memo from NIC (National Informatics Centre) circulating on Indian social media which states that Government placed an order to ban Chinese Apps on Google play store and Apple App Store. This is fake news. PIB (Press Information Bureau) an Indian government agency announced this as fake memo. This has been anounced by PIB on its official twitter handle PIBFactCheck.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple WWDC 2020 kick off on June 22</title><link href="https://techtelegrams.com/apple/Apple-WWDC-2020-kick-off-on-June-22/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple WWDC 2020 kick off on June 22" /><published>2020-06-21T20:20:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-21T20:20:00+05:30</updated><id>https://techtelegrams.com/apple/Apple-WWDC-2020-kick-off-on-June-22</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://techtelegrams.com/apple/Apple-WWDC-2020-kick-off-on-June-22/">&lt;p&gt;Apple’s WWDC (World Wide Developers Conference) 2020 kick off on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/wwdc20/&quot;&gt;June 22nd&lt;/a&gt; from Apple Park. Like any 
other tech event in 2020, this event also going to happen completely on online
due to the worst impact of COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apples-jump-from-intel-to-arm&quot;&gt;Apple’s Jump from intel to ARM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple might announce about its major Jump from intel to ARM chips for its MAC
desktops and latops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ios-14-launch&quot;&gt;iOS 14 launch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple will announce iOS 14 which is
expected to be more focused on stability and performance rather than new
features. And also there are rumours that Apple is going to &lt;strong&gt;rename
iOS to iPhoneOS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;video-guided-fitness-app-on-iphone&quot;&gt;Video guided fitness App on iPhone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deccanchronicle.com/technology/in-other-news/150320/apple-developing-a-free-fitness-app-for-guided-yoga-workout-and-much.html&quot;&gt;rumours&lt;/a&gt;
that Apple will bring a new Fitness App on its iPhone, which contains &lt;strong&gt;Video
guided Physical activity&lt;/strong&gt;. And the Apple Watch will track the activity and 
sync with other Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-carkey&quot;&gt;Apple CarKey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is expected to launch a new &lt;strong&gt;CarKey&lt;/strong&gt; feature on iPhone and Apple Watch,
which is a NFC car key to unlock the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ipados-14&quot;&gt;iPadOS 14&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year iPad was launched with iPadOS which is a forked version of iOS. And
this year is expected to add lot more features specific to iPad usage like
&lt;strong&gt;converting handwritten words into standard text&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;watchos-7&quot;&gt;WatchOS 7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are rumours that Apple is going to bring **oxygen level tracking on blood
** to WatchOS 7. And also it is expected to bring much more features related
to Covid19 Contact tracing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok Karmegam</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="MobilePhone" /><category term="Laptop" /><summary type="html">Apple’s WWDC (World Wide Developers Conference) 2020 kick off on June 22nd from Apple Park. Like any other tech event in 2020, this event also going to happen completely on online due to the worst impact of COVID-19 pandemic.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Motorola One Fusion Plus in India</title><link href="https://techtelegrams.com/mobilephone/Motorola-One-Fusion-Plus-in-India/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Motorola One Fusion Plus in India" /><published>2020-06-17T00:20:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-17T00:20:00+05:30</updated><id>https://techtelegrams.com/mobilephone/Motorola-One-Fusion-Plus-in-India</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://techtelegrams.com/mobilephone/Motorola-One-Fusion-Plus-in-India/">&lt;p&gt;Motorola launched
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.motorola.in/smartphones-motorola-one-fusion-plus/p&quot;&gt;One Fusion Plus&lt;/a&gt;
in Indian market, a new midrange smartphone with Moonlight White and Twilight
Blue colour option with a price tag of 16900 INR. White variant has full body
white including front, this is one of the unique White colour phone on the
market. It comes with a dedicated button for Google Assistants. It will be
available for sale from June 24th 2020 on Flipkart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;motorola-one-fusion-plus-specification&quot;&gt;Motorola One Fusion Plus Specification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Colour: Moonlight White and Twilight Blue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screen: 6.5 inch FHD+ IPS LCD with 19.5:9 aspect ratio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Processor: Snapdragon 730G&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Memory/Storage: 6GB memory and 128GB inbuild storage (expandable upto 1TB).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Battery: 5000mAh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charger: 18W Turbo Charger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Front Camera: 16MP with f/2.0 aperture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rear Camera: 64MP/8MP/5MP/2MP camera setup
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;64MP Main camera / 8MP ultra wide angle camera / 5MP macro shooter /
  2MP depth sensor&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ports: USB Type-C port and 3.5MM audio jack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network: Dual 4G VoLTE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speaker: Bottom mounted speaker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fingerprint Sensor: On back&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dimention: 162.9 x 76.9 x 9.6 mm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Body: Plastic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OS: My UX on top of Android 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motorola One Fusion Plus looks bulkier with 9.6 mm, that is mainly because
of accomodating 5000mAh battery in a 6.5 inch form factor. Build looks good
but not metal body. Overall it is a tough competitor on midrange segment
to Poco X2, Redmi Note 9 Max, Realme 6 Pro and Honor 9X Pro.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok Karmegam</name></author><category term="MobilePhone" /><category term="Motorola" /><category term="Android" /><category term="MidrangePhone" /><summary type="html">Motorola launched One Fusion Plus in Indian market, a new midrange smartphone with Moonlight White and Twilight Blue colour option with a price tag of 16900 INR. White variant has full body white including front, this is one of the unique White colour phone on the market. It comes with a dedicated button for Google Assistants. It will be available for sale from June 24th 2020 on Flipkart.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mi Notebook 14 Launch in India</title><link href="https://techtelegrams.com/laptop/Mi-Notebook-14-launch-in-india/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mi Notebook 14 Launch in India" /><published>2020-06-14T00:20:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-14T00:20:00+05:30</updated><id>https://techtelegrams.com/laptop/Mi-Notebook-14-launch-in-india</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://techtelegrams.com/laptop/Mi-Notebook-14-launch-in-india/">&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi the mobile phone market dominator in India
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/CVxu9c6ArZc&quot;&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; its first ever
laptop (
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mi.com/in/mi-notebook-14-horizon/&quot;&gt;Mi Notebook 14 Horizon&lt;/a&gt;) in
India.
And its competitve price starts from 41,999 INR and goes up to 59,999 INR.
This laptop comes &lt;strong&gt;without web camera&lt;/strong&gt;, and a separate web camera is
available to use via USB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mi-notebook-14-horizon-variants-and-prices&quot;&gt;Mi Notebook 14 Horizon Variants and prices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mi-notebook-i5-10210u-variants&quot;&gt;Mi Notebook i5-10210U variants&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;41,999 INR&lt;/strong&gt;: i5-10210U / Intel Graphics 620 / 256 GB SATA SSD /
8GB DDR4 RAM / Mi Webcam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;44,999 INR&lt;/strong&gt;: i5-10210U / Intel Graphics 620 / &lt;strong&gt;512&lt;/strong&gt; GB SATA SSD /
8GB DDR4 RAM / Mi Webcam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;47,999 INR&lt;/strong&gt;: i5-10210U / &lt;strong&gt;NVIDIA MX250&lt;/strong&gt; / &lt;strong&gt;512 GB SATA SSD&lt;/strong&gt; /
8GB DDR4 RAM / Mi Webcam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All the above three variant’s price are &lt;strong&gt;inagural price till 16th July
2020&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mi-notebook-i7-10510u-variants-horizon-edition&quot;&gt;Mi Notebook i7-10510U variants (Horizon edition)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;54,999 INR&lt;/strong&gt;: i7-10510U / NVIDIA MX250 / 512 GB SATA SSD / 8GB DDR4 RAM /
Mi Webcam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;59,999 INR&lt;/strong&gt;: i7-10510U / NVIDIA MX250 / &lt;strong&gt;512 GB NVMe PCIe SSD&lt;/strong&gt; / 8GB DDR4 RAM /
Mi Webcam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mi-notebook-14-specifications&quot;&gt;Mi Notebook 14 Specifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weight:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;i5 variant: 1.5kg&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;i7 variant: 1.35kg&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thickness:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;i5 variant: 17.9 mm&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;i7 variant: 17.15 mm&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Colour:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;i5 variant: Silver&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;i7 variant: Grey&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Body: Metallic body&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screen size: FHD Anti-glare display of 14 inch (35.56 cm)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screen to body ratio: 91%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screen Viewing angle: 178 Degrees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screen aspect ratio: 16:9&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooling Vents:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;i5 variant: Bottom mounted cooling vents&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;i7 variant: Side mounted cooling vents&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speakers: Bottom mounted speakers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ports:
  -i5 variant
      - USB 3.1 Port: 2
      - USB 2.0 Port: 1
      - HDMI Port: 1
      - 3.5mm Jack: 1
  -i7 variant
      - USB 3.1 Port: 2
      - USB 2.0 Port: 1
      - USB Type C: 1
      - HDMI Port: 1
      - 3.5mm Jack: 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Battery backup: 46Wh battery which provides up to 10 hours backup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charger: 65W charger. 0 to 50% charge in 35 mins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mi Smart Features
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mi Blaze Unlock: Unlock with Mi Band.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mi Smart Share: Transfer files between mobile phone and laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mi-notebook-14-offers-and-discounts&quot;&gt;Mi Notebook 14 Offers and Discounts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HDFC bank card provides No Cost EMI for 6 months with a cashback of 2000 INR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Ashok Karmegam</name></author><category term="Laptop" /><category term="Xiaomi" /><summary type="html">Xiaomi the mobile phone market dominator in India launched its first ever laptop ( Mi Notebook 14 Horizon) in India. And its competitve price starts from 41,999 INR and goes up to 59,999 INR. This laptop comes without web camera, and a separate web camera is available to use via USB.</summary></entry></feed>